PEOPLE LANGUE DE LA LANGUE DE L

Aron Caplan – Strategy and Planning Director

Highly experienced, professionally qualified strategist across creative and analytical aspects of marketing, covering B2C and B2B. Wide-ranging background, combining Digital Strategy, Brand Consultancy, Customer Insight, Behavioural Change, Strategic Communications, Customer Engagement and Online User Experience. Worked in global agency groups (M&C Saatchi, WPP, Havas, Omnicom) and on major brands (e.g. O2, British Gas, Microsoft, AXA, Pfizer, Tesco, BSkyB). Passion for finding innovative yet pragmatic solutions by understanding the underlying values, attitudes and beliefs of consumers and customers.

Key achievements

- Successfully delivered brand, digital and multi-channel marketing programmes, with proven ROI
 - o **O2** small business 2021 customer comms programmes, achieving over 60% sales uplift
 - Dyno brand redevelopment and digital transformation leading to a 27% increase in online bookings after launch and winner of The Drums brand extension strategy https://tinyurl.com/ydc2o3xy
 - AXA launch of two subsidiaries into the retirement market moving the brand from unknown to third most recognised brand in the market
 - o **BSkyB** achieving record satellite TV sales in month of Virgin Media cable TV launch
 - o Pfizer launch of patient online disease awareness programme commended by McKinsey
 - o Carling brand activation of live music sponsorship and winner of DMA Gold Award
 - Stansted Express 'Take the train' campaign, Out-of-Home gold at Travel Marketing Awards 2020
- Very high pitch winning success both as a freelance consultant and lead agency planner

Key experience and skills

- **Brand Consultancy and Strategy:** Leading brand development projects from defining what a brand stands for, its positioning, naming and its translation into powerful ideas and initiatives
- Integrated Marketing and Communications: Developing the detailed structure of activities, both online and offline to engage different customers and, in doing so, meet client business goals and objectives
- **Insight and Research:** Utilising expertise in both quantitative and qualitative methodologies with a strong ability to solve problems through combining analytical and creative thinking
- **Sector diversity:** Adapting techniques across numerous sectors with depth of competence in Healthcare, Financial Services, Utilities and Technology
- Mentoring and thought-leadership: Facilitating client workshops to initiate thinking, coaching junior strategists and wider agency teams in the craft of Strategic Planning and publishing articles
- **Presentation and writing:** Creating compelling proposals and presentations with a strong narrative and delivering them with enthusiasm and empathy.

Career summary

Strategy Director, M&C Saatchi London

Jan 2019 – Present

Clients: Retained - O2, Experian, Stansted Express, BNY Mellon. Project based includes - AXA
Health, Department for Education, Royal Mail, John Lewis Finance,

Planning Partner, Indicia

Sept 2014 – Feb 2018

 Clients: British Gas/Dyno, AXA, E.On, Pure Gym, Sunny Loans, Stanley Black & Decker, Renault, Nissan and Shop Direct

Freelance consultancy contracts, Withinsight Strategic Planning Ltd.

Aug 2005 - Sept 2014

(outside perm roles 2012-13, 2007-09 and 2018)

- Agencies: Wunderman, Kitcatt Nohr, Rapp, Proximity, MRM, Indicia, Sudler (Y&R Health), Digitas, Hall & Partners market research
- Agency Clients: Microsoft, Samsung, Bayer, Three, L'Oreal/Nestle skincare
- Client roles: BSkyB, Department of Health, SCA Hygiene

Director of Planning, Sudler & Hennessey

Jan 2012 - Sept 2013

• Clients: Boehringer Ingelheim, L'Oreal/Nestle skincare

Previous roles:

Planning Director, EHS Brann/Euro RSCG 4D Digital	2007-09
Clients - Tesco, News International	
Senior Brand Strategist, WWAV Rapp Collins Group/Zalpha	2001-05
Clients – Dell, Pfizer, Carling, British Gas, Cancer Research UK, Lloyds TSB, Wanadoo	
Senior Strategic Planner, Tequila Payne Stracey	1998-2000
Clients - BT, Fujifilm	
Consultant, Grey Integrated	1997-98
Clients: Post Office, Cable & Wireless	
Associate Partner, Conzept International brand consultancy	1991-97
Clients - Bass, Knorr, Freemans, Golden Wonder, Mars Confectionery, Thresher, Yardley	

Education and qualifications

MSc Marketing and Product Management, Cranfield Institute of Technology, Grade A BA(Econ) Honours, Economics and Social Studies, University of Manchester, Grade 2:1 DipM (Marketing Diploma), Chartered Institute of Marketing

Interests

Live music and festivals, running, quizzes